

# SAINUDHEEN K

### SENIOR UX DESIGNER

+91 7760540078

sainumechpd@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sainu123/

https://sainu.netlify.app/

https://www.behance.net/sainumechpd

### ABOUT ME

I'm a Lead UX/UI designer With a 10 years of experience in B2B, B2C, ERP mobile, and web applications, coupled with a **Master's** degree in product design from Coventry University United kingdom. I am proud to have received 4 UX/UI Design awards from 3 reputed fortune 500 companies.

### **EXPERIENCE**

• UX Lead
Aug 2022 - Present

Optum - United Health Group, Bengaluru

Strategic Planning
 Team leadership

Wire framing & Prototyping
 User Research

Project Management • Usability Testing

Collaboration with Cross-functional Teams
 Accessibility

Senior UX Designer Aug 2019 - Aug 2022

Yokogawa IA Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Bengaluru

Team Management
 User Research

Wire framing & Prototyping
 Usability Testing

Cross functional team collaboration
 Project Management

Senior UX Designer Sep 2017 - Aug 2019

Prime Focus Technologies, Bengaluru

Product Designer Nov 2014 - Feb 2017

Invntree Pvt Ltd, Bengaluru

Product Designer Jan 2009 - Aug 2012

Luk India Pvt. Ltd, Hosur

# **EDUCATION**

M.sc in Product Design 2012 - 2014

Coventry University United Kingdom - Regular

 Master Degree in Product Design covered areas such as usercentered design, Design management, Design Innovation, and Design technology.

• M.B.A 2010 - 2012

Indian School of Business Management - Distance

Diploma in Tool and die Engineering 2005 - 2008

Government polytechnic college, Thrissur, Kerala- Regular

# TOOLS

FigmaSketchZeplin

Adobe Creative Cloud
 Invision

### **AWARDS**

UX Design Award - Consumer Centric
 Optum - United Health group, Bengaluru

UX Design Award - Perfomance

Impact Award Project Support

Yokogawa IA Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Bengaluru

Optum - United Health group, Bengaluru

Design Award

Prime Focus Technologies, Bengaluru

Public Speaker & Trainer Award2019 & 2020

Toast Master International & Junior Chamber International

### **UX CERTIFICATION**

Design Thinking

2019- Distinction

Interaction Design Foundation Denmark

Google UX Design Professional Certificate

2019- Distinction
Google

# **SKILLS**

- Product Design
- User Experience Design
- Personas, Scenarios & IA
- Mobile, Web & ERP Design
- User Research
- Usability Testing
- Wireframe
- Visual Design & Prototyping
- Building a strong design system and Assets with UI standards
- Generating a strong mood board based on the data analysis
- Manage Team and work very closely with Stakeholders,
   Users, Designers, and Developers from Project Kick off to
   UX sign-off
- Stake holder interview, Competitor analysis, Data analysis and qualitative reviews from user research

# LANGUAGES

EnglishKannada

Malayalam

Hindi
 Tamil

Urudu